don't go live there we go he wasn't
showing a bread so welcome to our 12th
together tech board meeting otherwise
affectionately called fix our roll
Friday's carry thought I started a new
fire now this is one of the first ones
that I started so today we don't have
much on the agenda the same thing we
were talking about in process raising
which is this collective open collective
and it's a quick couple minute video so
we can launch that if we want and then
what you guys discussed before I was
coming in is the only other thing on the
agenda which was Kerry wanted access to
the knack tool and so maybe if you just
want to update people um as to why that
is or isn't working and what what that
looks like and then we can watch this
open collective video and discuss maybe
how we can use it the other tech or our
individual projects I mean it's it
doesn't go into the nitty gritty but
it's a good video to show what they're
trying to do so the first part is you
guys with the back the thing you guys
just discussed yeah I don't know alright
so what we were talking about prior was
uh we had the neck tool set up as sort
of a like a project list so that people
could sign up for accounts and manage
their own project so that we could have
a public-facing list to show here's
other projects that we're doing and to
start actually fulfilling some of the
things that we've been talking about but
that was designed around the idea of
people actually sort of signing up and
then managing their own projects and a
couple people had signed up I think I've
you know to to if your people had like
sort of added to their project so there
are a few on there but for the most part
I didn't gain a lot of traction and that
sounds like what Kerry wants to do is to
sort of have her actually manage a lot
of the lists and go and do the
interviews so that we know she can
figure out who's on what to sort of have
one person owning that and the knack
tool wasn't really designed for that so
it's theoretically possible if we really
wanted to do it that we could do that
but at that point it's a full redesign
so if she's already going ahead with CRM
then I think it makes more sense for her
to just go straight to this this here
route and then if there's any issues
then then we can revisit the neck tool
but for now I think it makes more sense
to just skip a knack and then when the
serum is available we can do an export I
grabbed the data that's in that tool to
push it over and I'm sure that she
probably has her own spreadsheet
somewhere of the projects that she's
been doing interviews with people in the
it can be a projects group so that's
where things are at I don't know if
Kerry wants to chime in with some of the
update on the CRM stuff yeah well like I
said I've just they're just about to
install Drupal and that uninstalled see
Odom's and basically it was it was just
to get a kind of died actually going and
as I said because I wanted to see where
you were with the nak stuff and maybe to
like update or laughs obviously if
that's the way to be built I think
probably I'll just waste and if there's
I know you withdrew probably can have a
media where he but the security is them
desert
security and advice notice on it from
Drupal saying some of it might not be so
secure but I don't know whether that's
something that could be just tweaked
with the module but there's a module
there that you know actually attached to
it that as its own wiki which would be
quite good but yeah I think at night
after II of everyone who's in the
project group and what they're up to
because it's not really easy to see
unless anybody you know they've
introduced themselves and you know if
someone comes along and I know a lot of
people have joined and he said they're
looking to collaborate on projects so
because for them to see who's doing what
where they are and what they're looking
for and I'll do that but as I said
someone got their own projects and I'm
looking for collaborators so I think if
we have something the kind of just
people can go to a glance and then see
what's what and then plus a list of so
they may be possible projects that are
brewing and you know ideas and stuff as
well that'd be really good as well so I
think that's all I've got to say on that
bomb hopefully I was also like her
it's done by the end of next week and
then that way um you can come and have a
play in it and because as I said you can
just have modules as you go and rather
than what I did last time was just sort
of like piled high with modules that I'm
I didn't even probably use you know I
mean so and I think that's about it
really
all right so like I said I'll actually
just gonna put the agenda in the um I
believe me you guys commit it in the
private chat so you can hello there's
literally in case um wants to add
something through it there it is
the other thing was just this is
something we're talking about using for
process raising and solution raising and
possibly carries ones it looks like it's
it's a cool project this is all I've
done is looked at it so I haven't looked
at the website yet but the video itself
sinkholes it can talk about after we
watch it it's a couple minutes
something you're not okay dude do we
know if streamer can share audio when
you're sharing yeah okay stop screaming
sure screen I think I just needed to i
had it all ready to go so he wouldn't
have to do this but share audio there's
a little clicking button you have to
take it in order to share it and then
share will go right here
alright happened making it easy for
people to collaborate between them
outside triangles as open community is
working for our common goal call them
circles collectives of people working
together on software community projects
activism just about anything you could
think of this circle is a collective
called sphere you they build open-source
software like many circles they are open
and flexible
spero has contributors and users around
the world and it isn't owned by anyone
it's hard being a circle in a world
designed for triangles spheria sometimes
needs things like a bank account and a
way to pay taxes but they don't want to
stop being this circle the pyramid
company loves furio's open source
software it's critical to their business
and they want to support it but in our
world triangles can only give money to
other triangles because they need things
like invoices open collective is a home
for circles in a triangular world we
provide the tools circles need to thrive
we make it easy for circles to fundraise
accept sponsorship and pay expenses
without needing to become a triangle
everything on open collective is fully
transparent giving circles and their
supporters access to financial info
whenever they need it we take care of
taxes admin reporting accounting so
sphere EO can focus on their code and
their community now circles and
triangles can live happily ever after
and together we can start smoothing out
the corners of this triangular world
cool it wasn't I didn't get to the so
into it but it did seem like a perfect I
really hope the tools there may it's a
blockchain thing like I think there even
if it's not blockchain right now they're
looking to make it so no no because like
though I want them to work together like
Commons when it comes out to be able to
have something that I can sign on and be
part of all of these things and I want
to end as a SERP as someone who is
starting many a circle I want to be able
to to create something like this field
to bring people on board but maybe this
does do what Commons does as well or
come in whatever the one other one is
that was supposed to come out in June
and has not yet like come on right well
I deserve I'd opened coop info on
YouTube and they've got a full video of
them talking about it and actually going
in and showing you how it works because
you don't really get that from the
website when you go onto it so it's all
a bit of a deep dive into it and I'm
basically you don't even have to have a
bank account you can just Church what
you need is a fiscal house someone who's
a legal identity legal entity ie
business doesn't matter what business
the arts the legal entity and they've
got you needs an admin person and I
think and you need a stripe account and
you need to PayPal account so those are
the main things that you need for it but
what I liked about it most of all is
that you didn't have to turn yourself
into a business and you didn't have to
go through all that so there's just
three ways so if you've got no no bank
account whatsoever and just you have
people on there who are fiscal host will
do that for you and if you're I've got a
bank account they'll be able to there's
there's plans that they've got you can
have two to five projects I think it's
$25 and 1/2 plus 5% and handling fees
for stripe and stuff like that as well
so III think it's really brilliant
because I've said you know if you want
to try and do something and you want to
wake or like we said provide
for the company but you don't want to
turn yourself into an entity it's really
good and everything's transparent so you
can see what's going going in you set
the if you've got donations and
memberships whatever you want you can
actually set that yourself you know and
the only thing is cuz I know they've got
fiscal hosts on there but my kid gets
with a fiscal house I Drive it up
somebody do if there's a relationship
and there's some trusts they'd rather
you just go into a physical host because
they think they charge extra on top of
that and as I said if you've got no
relationship with them you might not
want to have you don there so I was
going to ask my friends if you'd be
interested in being a physical host so
we got started and I think maybe take
the two to five package on and then see
you know if he would do that cuz I don't
know the relationships in there maybe we
can take it over and then off as many
projects as you like and start
collectives under that you know as time
goes on but III think it's amazing and
because as I said just the thought of
having to go down the business route or
turn yourself into a charity or a social
enterprise or whatever
you shouldn't have to turn yourself into
anything you know I mean if you want to
do stuff you should you shouldn't be
able to do it and but that's them yeah I
love it I can't wait from you mate to
say yeah
like I said I just watched that video
and you got excited for the fact that we
don't have to do that because that's
someone who wants to start fires and I
don't even want to start my own YouTube
channel for the new fires like it's like
okay well let's see if it goes anywhere
before that happens the idea of
incorporating something and then anytime
you want to crowdfund you have to of
course you need to have your own bank
account your corporation to accept money
and I do wonder how open collective
works with crowdfunding like if you had
a Kickstarter account or something that
could go into your open collective I
don't or you know like your your fiscal
sponsor and then that's more of I'll
look into it it's like you to answer
that but I would love if you um were
able to send Carrie be the other video
that you watched I thought this was the
one that you were talking about but if
you I know that we won't watch it now
but if I would love to watch it and we
can add it to the UM to the chat so that
people can see what it is as well if
you're able to find it I'm curious how
international is it I mean accounting
okay but under which jurisdiction
exactly because if I want to get money
from say us the way I used to do it was
I got paid in crypto and I had my own
business which is second UK term a
self-employed I got my company's name
but I was essentially on my own just
visible to the system as this company
something like this so I paid my taxes
and social insurance but um like in
Polish institutions and if they offer
accounting my question is is it the best
thing or is it like accounting in
general and then something else needs to
happen before you can get money if you
are if you happen to be not from us so
I'm sure on the video that I'm gonna put
in the room
the links and that and there on the
video might be set there's people in
Belgium they're all over the place you
know that you know probably the best
thing to do would get a fiscal host
using your based in your country and I
know there's loads of this called hosts
I think and but as I search it doesn't I
know the I think the main one is set in
the US but I know there's the social
change agency that you're in the UK and
another from the open copy road the guy
and it was on it talking about it and
showing it was saying that they had in
Belgium so they'll probably M be someone
who could act as a fiscal host in in
Poland or even if you knew somebody
who's got a business in Poland you'd be
willing to do that em for you and then
you could maybe set it up that way and
but yeah there's pretty international
but I I just have one look at that air
link for you so you can go watch it
later I mean I'm all set
it's just I actually spent time on the
earth wondering and making sure I am
illegal and yeah if someone else wanted
to do the same and without actually
going to the institutions and
registering as whatever I mean would it
be possible to just apply mm-hmm
register with open collective and never
have to worry about and if you know it's
an open question are you check for
myself later seemed like a fairly
important because that's I mean part of
the attraction to me is that you do have
members all over the world you don't
necessarily need to worry that someone's
from Australia and they're paying you
and doing that but the company itself
needs to be in one jurisdiction and that
looks like that's part of what open
collective does is remove that but how
could they you think they can't you have
to be doing taxes and accounting in a
jurisdiction exactly the problem is that
each and every financial jurisdiction in
the world wishes to
keep the businesses to themselves so if
I always the problem when I worked in
virtually in u.s. or in UK but
physically being presents not there just
in in Poland of course I was I didn't
have any choice about it I needed to pay
taxes in Poland because this is where
I'm physically at the moment so yeah
really curious how they solved it if
they did solve it yeah have you got the
link for the forums and Matus because I
was reading through all the
documentation about that I've been sent
you the link if you want stuff as it
came
vot write the taxes I think they pay
would be regards to any money right yeah
I think they are collected because
they're the fiscal host charges Europe
so we charge you for the plan so I think
what they do is take care of the taxes
of the money they get from you but as a
self autonomous collective I think any
taxes that you know like as I know in
the UK if you're an individual and you
want to do something like a sides also
and that I think it allowed to end up to
a thousand pounds before you you know
you consider for any tax but as part of
that collective you responsible for that
in your country but I think as I said I
think there when they say taxes they
take care of the taxes and they might
have a penis and you would do all four
laughs or yeah but then they charge you
to Christ but if you take care of it
yourself I think I think as I said I
think the taxes they take care of it's
just that the money they get off you and
obviously the the fees and stuff and
maybe their the interest that gets paid
towards them I think they take care of
that side of things but you have to take
care of the the other stuff yourself
which is all
you know me but what you know and if you
freelance because I think you can do as
an individual as well sort of your
freelance as I said you'd be taking care
of you know things anyway but as I said
I've got a friend who just bookkeeping
accountancy and stuff so I've spoke to
her about it so that's why I was what
animator to do do a four-dose because
I'm does the three will stand in you
could do things and then hopefully do
bookkeeping an admin for other
collectives as well you know I mean and
keep them straight but yeah so I think
that I think when we talk about the
taxes is that the taxes that they pay on
on what you pay them you know me so you
don't have to worry about any of that as
I said as I said it took to you to run a
collective as you as you see fit
obviously all the laws in each different
country applied differently so you have
to do that you know I mean so just
imagine you know like the taxman coming
to my door and asking okay so you live
here and the money you have go check
with them you don't save my name's Dave
I don't know about you Jess yeah here's
the link
yeah Dave yeah so I linked I linked the
thing you sent in under the Facebook
post so that anyone can find it if they
go to game B projects and we can follow
it from here it is an hour and a half so
oh definitely won't be watching it
during this I do wonder hopefully this
isn't successful on enterprise hopefully
it stays in existence because it does
seem like a cool
well think worries me a little bit that
they have like an open collector they
have 98 subscribers but they do have
6000 views on that video and the other
one was that's on the brief brief one
so that's all I'm people in today and
then it can't find the other one now oh
yeah I'm a hundred twenty four views in
two hundred twenty seven subscribers we
need subscribers you mean on their
YouTube channel yeah okay yeah
I wouldn't find out to worry I've worked
for preferred you know moderately sized
companies they didn't have a big YouTube
following because that wasn't their
thing that's just the open co-op though
that's not your and collective itself
that's just them like talking about it
so the open collector was quite large
because if you go to the site you can
see all the people all the groups and
what they've got going on this one to
top them and that's good because that's
what they need more than they need
YouTube followers they need people who
are using it and paying their twenty
five dollars a month and when they have
transactions collecting their five
percent which is yeah go check it out
I'm sure it'll start some new fires well
now that this exists I can start all the
things for Raja upper silesia
what have you done carry alright lots of
fun all right well I don't know we're
talking about for the rest of the hour
we don't necessarily need to stay on and
make time up if we're done with but is
there anything we need to discuss for
together tech is there anything anyone
needs help with for their own project
versus of course the bigger project is
like how we can I'm new in all of our
projects but if any of them are kind of
pertinent to the preferred Li live
together tech but even if it's wick
election I just want to ask am i its
together tectonic began that I'm the
main name they do we have our own do if
we have together tech dot something dot
org today beautiful do it anything with
it that's a whole other question okay
there's something up there I
made a Wix website and then this woman
this lovely woman off of Craigslist made
it into a non Wix website for free but
it's still basically the same
information that was there two years ago
if you could send me that another look
because as I said them because of the
hosting accounts I've got up in-house
host as many websites of the life you
know I mean and I'm just trying to think
about the what's up now so wanted to say
put a card right there
howdy vember what was gonna say right so
oh shut up now
Oh Matus right oh you get an army
decides it's him how you getting on with
everything done yeah it's all good
I had a moment of doubt yesterday when I
looked at the structure you started to
create in in in my project and I
realized how much is missing in terms of
the user interface it's not that the
functionality is not that it's just I
might not have thought deeply enough
about how to make it to look when there
is actually data in it so because I
think as I said like I said you've got
it all in unit so you know if you think
a so when you get so like me coming
along who's going ooh what's this
what's that you know I mean so I already
deleted this navigation system by
accident no problem with the codes which
I think I fixed but it was not so I was
for the past 24 hours I was thinking how
to make it look a bit better
mmm and I think I mean I have some ideas
so I'll be working on it tonight and
next few days I think but in the
meantime I improved the accounts I seen
what you see and you are now able to
edit details about yourself basically so
it doesn't look like there's nothing in
in the in the notes in the window so
that looks better and I'm about to
improve connections between notes so it
doesn't look like a spaghetti thing
which is very undercooked spaghetti
red license so yeah improve that and yes
I still don't know when is the right
moment to share it more publicly
publicly instead of just talking
individually to people I've got a few
odd ideas about that but I says I love a
child yeah I mean i GL I do you get
always weekly lectures with elections
good they working well with asthma
douche
we got the gift have created it got the
hosting I've got it actually up at F dot
wiki election con right now it's still
like the early you know pre-alpha
framework but we'll be adding on
features to get it to where it needs to
be so it's going good okay so we can go
a lot then if you want yeah I mean
there's not much to look at yet it's
very early days framework but that was
sort of like as I said just the
framework to sort of bolt stuff onto so
we've got it to where like the very
first sort of draft specs were it's not
useful yet but that's because my initial
specs weren't useful like it wasn't
meant to be there yet
but yeah you can go there and view it
and technically you can create an
account and that type of thing okay what
have you think sorry what are the other
things I've just remembered what you
know that I am blockchain hollow chain
and crypto currencies and hermit you
said you want set up for kind of me and
and that and maybe I'm a chart and I
said because I don't have I don't have a
clue about any of it so I'm just taking
a deep dive into everything just now so
have we said everything to look out
right I don't know what that is so I'm
gonna have to go look so that's gonna
take me we were to get me around or a
lot I suggest in the meeting because in
the past few days I I'm not sure why but
I not noticed in a few different places
that people were thinking about
the blockchain and how useful it is for
everything and in the past I had a few
discussions precisely about about that
so the meeting would be more about an
overview what this and why it is not a
silver bullet for everything that is
wrong because what I also noticed
especially in the crypto community is
and especially initially two three years
ago when the boom started the crypto was
going to solve everything and it was
like this it is precisely what we need
what was missing from the world and now
it is here and now when we start using
it we will be will be able to fix
everything like kill all the corrupt
banking system remove the politicians
the even like the law that was going to
be covered in crypto there was something
like that as well and blockchain is a
wonderful and amazing technology for
sure it's just it's not quite going to
solve everything like in one go
so so what we do right now to be honest
we don't need blockchain as much as some
people might think so in theory
everything that you can do on the
blockchain you can do in other
technologies it's just for some users
blocking as the right tool to use and
yeah that's the basic description and
hello chain is not quite a blockchain so
use of coaching is slightly different
and yeah for that I prefer someone who
knows Oh Jane better than then I to
speak about it but yeah
coaching is even more amazing technology
then the lock chambers and it it's going
to as far as I understand is going to
have more users and it's it it's better
in terms of well one of the things it
does not burn as much coal as Bitcoin
for example so you know it's quite
famous how we kind and other pure lock
chain technologies they use energy like
crazy right so it's not not very good in
that respect is there a nature of block
trainers at a nature of trying to mine
for the unique IDs that you need for
stuff like Bitcoin the point is you need
all nodes in the network to agree on the
next node to be added that's also just a
crazy amount of traffic to keep
everything in sync
not even traffic it's the crazy amount
of computations down separately on each
node in the in the network something
like this so that's that's why it's not
very energy efficient yeah I think I'm
that's that's that's the very short
story about I know there's work down on
making it more energy efficient there is
like plenty when you read about I don't
if you know other projects they do
wonderful work to make it faster make it
more efficient make it more robust I
think but yeah my point was blocking has
specific uses and right now in game B in
general the use for it is it's not like
foundation for everything
I've just remembered what I was gonna
say before so you know that I'm the
project's about sort of like the
different types of economies like
capitalism socialism and all of that
would wick elections be a place you know
when you were saying there how to find
the collect information so when I'm
researching information into all these
things about what's what's true and
what's false I just wondered whether
with elections I'd be able to use that
in terms of knowing outer or to get all
that information once it finds it that's
one of sort of the later stage goals is
to have a lot of information about like
just the systems of government sort of
the theoretical ones and then the actual
like how countries operate individually
have what the actual rules are in place
mostly the real world applications
because you know if you talk about
socialism well that means a million
different things right like are we
talking about Sweden are we talking
about Mao was China like what do we mean
when we say socialism and technically
they're all correct but they're also all
wrong so it yeah it's the goal is mainly
just to provide information just sort of
help people decide how to vote and a
part of that is you know if you're
voting for president or you're voting
for mayor okay but what does that person
do what are their rights and their
responsibilities and all that so that
you know what you're actually voting for
and then like okay if they have these
responsibilities here's what sort of
skill set that person should probably
have whoever's in that role should you
know know about these sort of things
because they're gonna have these four
responsibilities just any sense yeah
yeah that makes sense because as I said
I was just thinking of sort of like ways
of them other sort of information out
there and and half the time you don't
know whether it's true or not and
digging through the research shows me
may was to get all the research turn
into all them areas then with James
imasu she was like develop that and to
kind of like muffin you know all the
different
the world of that but from now I had you
know as I said least linmark truth Adam
marriage counseling with humanity and
post capital which I thought was
brilliant
well I've spoke to Rhys and asked him
what he'd be interesting at because
what's all that information was there
what I would like to do was of him like
that marriage counseling polyp a leg
trauma counselling with Humanity in
campus at Ames communism and stuff like
that but do it with actors I'd like to
do with actors and maybe so they do that
so they get you know an audio play kind
of sort of thing that the dialogue and
that you know sort of like him Humanity
in communism and at the trauma counselor
you know I mean to do like that because
I know I would scare and I restore me
that Alex Kennedy may be interested in
doing her film animation okay but but
yeah so that's the second of like
transmedia storytelling because of yeah
this is a trustees yeah cuz I think
people have got right because you've got
people who watch and you've got people
who listen right and sometimes you know
a lot of people my age like to listen to
things of the doing things on the
computer and I was I was looking at that
gen Z post and the main game before them
and although sauce like you know the
James II is going oh I'm afraid to watch
videos to take in information and that
so in terms of sort like getting the
right information
it's got to be engaging for them to
watch so because as I said a lot of
people have got this this view of
socialism you know it's wonderful and
that I'm the same with communism and I
thought when we do this or like trauma
counselor at their you know humanity
this you know communism enough and I
know there's a lot of good bits in each
of the economic systems there's probably
good stuff in in each and every one of
them but it's the horrors that get
caused that people don't seem to know
about and as I said if they're not
interested in history they don't know
for him but then you just need to be
aware of what you know but core so I
think if you do that in a kind of
engaging conversation where you know
someone's playing the part of a trauma
counselor and stuff you know I mean
that's what sparked that off anyway I
spoke Teresa wrote it and he said to
keep you posted
Jason stone and you said he'd like to be
involved as well so I'm just looking for
what was about a place where I can start
gathering the research and then
everybody can chip in and as and when
they've got time because I know
everybody's doing their own projects and
the oven got a lot of time to go
mooching about I think so which I'm
quite happy to do and but as I said what
we've got a place without that's the
kind of transmedia storytelling and I
know him one of the things that we add
was about science fiction as well so and
if there's any other things that you'd
like me to sort of like be on the
lookout because I love Richard on the
internet and fines and things and things
pop up when I start look if you don't
have been so him and do all sorts of
bits and pieces out of that as well so
at least there'll be a place that stuff
can be poor people can answer it but as
I said at what the right information not
what so like someone you know of me
because they heard someone say about him
and found that you know about there was
something mentioned about ethnic
Africans selling other Africans on that
and I found this article that said you
know in whatever century it was the
African Chiefs sent a delegation to
Paris in London because they were upset
about the abandoning of slavery or the
banning of it so they sent a delegation
to complain you know I mean because
obviously that could have been what he
supply but he had someone say oh that's
preposterous nah that's although there's
a load of information nobody knows about
history but something floating about and
it'd be nice to know the truth to stop
even if it doesn't you know even if it's
quite a lot of people I'd rather know
what's true and right rather than so
it's like you know someone else's spin
on it you know I mean yeah I would
absolutely like to do a solution raising
on each of like the specific to
information right so economics not
solving economics but understanding
economics history is a big one where we
don't have a full picture of it how do
you decide what's right how do you
decide what's wrong how do you visualize
it because it's like is the information
true
even if you make an amazing video if one
things off then it kind of you know like
it's hard to go back in and fix it I
would love I love the idea of the trauma
counselling with humanity but if you're
gonna do if communist I'm you also need
to do with capitalism because the big
thing is is it's like everyone's like oh
there's these hundreds of millions of
deaths like capitalism by communism
which is absolutely true and yet every
day all nearly every death on this
planet is attributed to capitalism
people starving to death people who have
either not enough to eat or way too much
to eat a lot of it is designed like it's
like okay so like almost like communism
is your ex that you're going to go
through what capitalism is your current
abusive partner that's like yeah wait a
was first talking abut I was kind of
picturing like a skit that was almost
like a couples counseling where one
person is you know socialism communism
and one person is capitalism they're
going back and forth list well you did
this and you did that and then the
person trying to figure out what that I
think that one could be you know
probably a good combination of
entertaining and educational actually
this isn't just be chanted to meme some
isms and that's all we all know
so a me speech you chew cuticle means
and isms that's what a truthful isms you
know the truth about all these as I said
that thing that gets tainted to an ism
when I said individualism is getting
frowned upon
collectivism this and that you know we
never did everything as I said this good
fits in all of it for him I said you
don't get to know the truth and there's
nobody out there who can't even tell you
that what the problem with this is
exactly the same program as we've any
other big subject I once upon a time I
used to discuss like religious stuff
with especially about cathodic Church
because that's the most popular one in
Poland like 90 percents assumed to be
Catholics and we it's like we all know
what problem with culture is right more
or less
but to talk about it exclusively in
terms of how bad it is it's kind of
missing the point
it's the subject is way too big to be
categorized only on one side of the
equation and that good bits and about
bits and pieces about about this and to
talk about all of them I don't think
that's again possible because there is
always going to be a counter argument
and okay
this was built good this was bad and it
can continue and I'm not sure if it's
totally productive use of time and
seeming out I well I I've seen it in
action so I'm totally biased against and
I understand it as an idea that is very
good as an idea but once it's built into
production it ends badly and it's
inevitable it's just there is no single
example of it's going right I'm afraid
so it's just up at the full picture just
be able to have the full picture of
everything you know I mean and then make
up your mind what side you want to join
but it's just some way to have the full
picture of everything you know but what
I'm afraid of is the big picture is too
big for anyone's head
that's what dr. Berger says that right
now those subjects are too big for any
single individual to be able to keep in
in like in one mind it's just yeah too
big so it's necessary for us to like see
what we can see from any system and
that's what people do they prefer to see
the bright side or the bath
and then stick to it and then it's just
easier and it's not you oh it might not
it's not even that it's easier it's the
only way possible sometimes but myself I
am doing as I tried to always remember
to argue about specific points and I
always a disclaimer that and I do argue
against communists and against
capitalism and against any other system
there is because each of them has points
but I always add a disclaimer that yes I
point out specific problems but it's not
that I think that this the system is
totally wrong hundred percents and
there's nothing to be learned from there
is nothing good about it right yeah I
think we're just getting fairly close to
the hour I just want to find out from
Kerry with like the together tech
specifically the game beef Facebook
group gave me projects just together
attack at the moment um you're kind of
managing people coming in right we're
not accepting them because you're you're
doing the entry and I don't want it
likes except someone and then have you
not be able to see their answers is
there anything that you need help with
in that how is that going and would it
help you to have a calendar or set up or
something or you could put in your
schedule and people could just schedule
a yes because and I was gonna say I like
I said Facebook shows you the answers
but it doesn't keep them so I already
figured that out enough since I are and
then I've started keeping a spreadsheet
of the answers and stuff but as I said
there's a lot of people who were not
answering the questions right sometimes
you know you made a lot of time you come
back so and just leave it for quite a
few days and see and wait yeah it's just
trying to get some some a bit more
engagement
you know and I've read a few people
asking them would you introduce yourself
or not and I don't seem to get no answer
so so I don't understand why you're
joining a group if you don't want to you
don't want to take any part of it you
know I really like and I notice loads of
people there and I don't know people
maybe not feel right enough about
jumping in or the the topics that are
getting posted or not so I'm just trying
to fight figured out how to get people
more engaged in either telling us what
they're doing or you know be more
interested because I know of quite a few
people and wanting to join projects and
but as I said it's just a trying to find
the right balance of trying to get them
so they say well look this is the
project that I'm on trust now and this
is what so I don't know whether it's
just a case of its Facebook and although
they're not a stage they're ready to
post the project yeah but it'd just be
nice to get some sort of conversations
going about different things but because
as I said I haven't spoken to a lot of
people yeah
so I don't know what their interest is
and I know be posted because I said some
people just post at the intro and then
you never get to hear from them again so
I don't know whether it's a time issue
or so I'm a bit struggling as if or
whether they just think I'm a bit scary
as I go so no I mean what you're doing
is definitely a step up to what we were
doing so don't feel like it needs to be
all of the like you don't need to have
an entry
um interview with every single person if
that's overwhelming for you that's kind
of what what you then there is going to
be a difference in participation but
also some of the people might be BOTS
right and if they're not responding to
anything and they're not answering the
questions answering the questions and
having at least a voice conversation is
a good way to know that there's a human
being somewhere in there hopefully but
it doesn't overwhelm me because I love
doing this I love talking to people and
finding out what they're up to and
because then you see what what's out
there as I said after about all is not
knowing what's out there and when you've
got projects going on and you may be
thinking of something if you don't have
if you don't know what's out there
you know because I said you might get
started in some way down the line you
think oh my god was about twenty people
doing that you know yeah no there's just
somebody came into the Facebook he was
like we need to access how about an open
source Facebook I'm like yeah you get on
that that's your project but what else
do you do every other Facebook group
which is people join because the name
appears on there like suggestions you
may want to join this so they click
automatically and they don't bother with
questions because they are not
interested in the thing but they clicked
because that's what people do they click
and the end result is out of every
hundred people 90 of them is going to be
silent and they're not going to leave
because people never leave Facebook
groups oh I mean no no so it's like one
percent is going to post something and
to be active participants ten percent is
going to write from time to time and at
least follow what's going on and ninety
percent is going to be silent forever I
mean this is what I observe in every
basically every other group I mean so
when you start you have this totally
different proportions when you start
only people who are really interested to
join because they know it from the start
that's such a group exists and they join
and they do stuff and they talk and
right after when you get above I don't
know hundred two hundred members the
proportions are changing and then people
join who are not interest who do not
know what they are joining really but
still we can let them in because there
is always a chance that one of the
hundreds is going to look into it small
and you know have the sparkle yeah this
is what I really wanted although I
didn't know
and then they're going to be more active
oh okay I just feel like you know you're
gonna get anything going you've got our
kind of make connections then try and
build a relationship and from that cook
trust comes and then you can see along
the way I'm a joke but that's same well
with anything surely even if you want to
collaborate with someone you've got to
build a relationship there you know but
I just don't know and it's struggling it
about cuz I don't want to be dead pushy
you go oh you must talk to me or else
you know I really there's just like you
know and so I'm a bit unsure but I just
try to know what it was doing and I'll
just try and find interesting things
which help there's some people who've
when I've asked to talk to them they put
me they've sent me their link for their
calendar right for their like yeah
schedule time and then itself tells us
it sets us both up I don't use that
because I can't like I don't have a
specific amount of time that I can be
available from 9:00 to 3:00 it's like
yes I need one hour during that time
there are never enough spoons but if you
know your schedule and you know when
you're open instead of you needing to
reach out to everyone individually in
the welcome message hey please introduce
yourself if you're interested in setting
up a one-on-one here's my calendar right
and then they can it puts the onus on
them and then if as long as they're
humans I think we're in even honestly
there's probably BOTS already in there
as long as like they do answer the
questions and if they don't answer the
questions and they've been asked to
answer the questions
yeah they don't need to be in like they
you get least need to do the first part
so we know that you are in a human being
and you have something you kind of know
what this group is I would be and then
the needing to talk to you is like
that's an amazing added benefit where
they can find out what's going on and
find out what project if they don't want
to take you up on that but that's that's
on them and yeah I think this is my room
will kind of give like a reason to to to
talk to you especially if you're
somebody that has a project they seem
like kind of our top tier like the
people that we really want to be active
and should in theory want to participate
more so you know taking an audience
approaches
to participate in the conversations and
then you've got sort of the people who
don't have a project but want to see
what projects are out there are actively
looking and then you'll have the lurkers
that are just just watching but as we
said like if one in a hundred becomes
either you know a project like how many
who contributes or they start a project
then they can you know say hey Kerry I
just had an idea for project now I want
to meet with you I think if you sort of
like intentionally separated out where
it's kind of it's optional if you still
have to answer the questions so we're
trying to deflect BOTS but then it's if
you have a project they should be
actively you'd like hunting you down
they should be trying to talk to you
they get put on that list because then
that's that's the list that if you want
to contribute hey great go here if you'd
like you know an actual one-on-one
conversation cool I'm open to that as
well yeah cuz I thought I think him much
and I'd like to get to the stage where
I'm a much in people who are looking the
people who've got you know I mean I'm
I'm asked for students of God drawer
full of spoons Jubilee the next part and
I used to play spoons and we used to
play them on people's heads and not hey
so that's it legacy a drawer full of
spirits of all he got he lives of folks
but I've got loads of spirits
that you do it's hilarious because I'm
like I'm like I'm worried about your
spoons like I'm like how do I care for
you but like you're in charge of that
and if you don't have a spoon disability
no one else needs to worry about it it's
not like free like you're burning the
candle at both ends and you're taking
too much on but that's me that's that's
yeah I don't need to do that for you you
do have an abundance of students all
right is there anything else you would
like to talk about on the agenda like
that should be fit in here before we say
goodbye to YouTube I can't think about
anything at the moment but and yes
people want I just came to check me like
I'm open for that and so if you don't
know just message me and let me know and
but yeah I thought that'd be I think
that's all of us ages now correct I'll
just end it then saying that tomorrow
morning we have our roundtable taking
place at 9:00 a.m. Pacific Standard Time
we do that every Saturday morning even
though it's the fourth of July because
we none of us are getting our American
so the American ones can choose to come
in or not come in that is the beauty of
having you in a world community is that
we can still I still at my solution
raising on Canada Day it was amazing I
don't practice kind of today all right
goodbye YouTube and Facebook we will see
you tomorrow morning